CURRICULUM VITAE

Dr. Priyanka Gupta, Ph.D.

302, 19 B Sarvodaya Chs., Bimbisar Nagar, Goregaon (East), Mumbai - 400065

Mob: +91 99589 14535

E-mail: dosarpriyanka@gmail.com, priyanka.gupta462@gmail.com



Profile:

A goal-oriented researcher with six years of bench-work experience (wet lab) with Biochemistry background. I am skilled in molecular diagnostics, molecular biology, biochemical and biophysics techniques, data interpretation, and scientific writing, looking for a challenging and rewarding position in an organization.

Educational Qualification:

■ **Ph.D. in Life Sciences:** All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi in

2021.

B.Ed. in Biological Sciences:
 M.Sc. in Biochemistry:
 Bundelkhand University in 2013 with 72.3%
 Bundelkhand University in 2010 with 78.3%.

B.Sc. in Ind. Microbiology & Chemistry: Bundelkhand University, 2008 with 68%.

Certificate Course on ISO 15189:2012 Medical Laboratories – Requirements for quality & competence and internal audit course.

Certificate training program- Fundamentals of Computers (July 2011-Dec 2011)

National/State Level Exams:

Qualify GATE Life Science 2012 with score 361 and AIR 965.

Qualify Uttar Pradesh Common Eligibility Test-Ph.D.-2012.

Work Experience and Employment details

Institute/Company	Designation and Department	Duration	Areas of work
Haffkine Institute, Mumbai	Research Associate Dept of Biochemistry & Cell Biology	24 th Feb 2022 – till date	Genomics (WGS, NGS), Bioinformatics & ATC
Spice Health Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai	Senior Scientific officer Department: Lab Operation (ICMR & NABL Certified diagnostic Lab)	4 th Feb 2021-16 th Sep 2021 (7 Months, 12 days)	Virology (Covid-19 RT-PCR), Molecular Biology LIMS, Quality Control
AIIMS, New Delhi	Laboratory Technician Clinical Biochemistry Division Department of Laboratory Medicine	9 th April 2014 – 2 nd April 2015 (11 months, 24 days)	Clinical Biochemistry Data interpretation and Reporting

Research Experience:

Institute	Designation and Department	Project Title and duration	Areas of work
Haffkine	Research Associate	Genome Sequencing of SARS Cov-2	Genomics, Virology,
Institute, Mumbai	Dept of Biochemistry & Cell Biology	24 th Feb 2022 – till date	Bioinformatics
AIIMS,	Ph.D. Research Scholar	"Development of Multiplex real time PCR (qPCR) assay for simultaneous detection of hepatitis viruses (A-G) in	Molecular Biology, Virology (Hepatitis),
New Delhi	Dept. of Laboratory Medicine (Principal Investigator: Prof. M. Irshad & Dr. Sudip K. Datta)	serum" 3 rd Aug 2015 - 25 th March 2021 (5 Years, 7 Months)	Biochemistry, Bioinformatics
IITR,	Trainee (M.Sc. Dissertation)	"Assessment of Chemical, Biochemical and Phytotoxic properties of Soil Influenced by Heavy Metals"	Analytical Chemistry, Metal Analysis,
Lucknow	Metal Analysis Laboratory (Principal Investigator: Dr. Nasreen Gazi Ansari	11 th Jan 2010 - 10 th June 2010 (6 months)	Biochemistry, Phytotoxicity, Enzymology
Biotech Park,	Trainee	"Biotechnology & Bioinformatics" (Industrial training program) 1st June 2009 –30th June 2009	Biotechnology (PTC) Molecular Biology, Bioinformatics
Lucknow.	HH Biotechnologies Pvt. Ltd.	(1 months)	Diomiormatics

Technical Experience and Skills:

- Genome Sequencing of SARS Cov-2 using ONT platform, Cell culture and cloning (ATC; Vero cells & PTC; callus culture).
- Experiment design, laboratory instrument and assays validation, PCR, RT-qPCR, Multiplex RT-PCR (MX3005P), Isolation of DNA and RNA, Gel Electrophoresis (Agarose and SDS-PAGE), Protein Purification, Western Blot, Immunological assays; ELISA and CLIA, Primers and Probes designing for detection of different viruses (singleplex to multiplex), Bioinformatics tools; Multiple sequence alignment, BLAST, FASTA, Crustal Omega and Graph pad prism 6.
- Covid-19 RT-PCR testing (BioRad), analysis and final reporting, Laboratory Operational Management, Team lead, LIMS, ISO 15189: 2012, ISO 9001.
- Clinical biochemistry parameters using Automatic analyzers
- Enzymatic activity determination with UV-Vis, Analysis of Biochemicals, Heavy metal analysis using AAS and ICP, Nano-drop, Bioassay (Phytotoxicity) technique, Dry heat and Microwave digestion, Thin Layer, Size exclusion and Affinity Chromatography, pH meter, conductivity, melting point, Titrations.

Qualified Awards/Grants/Scholarship:

- Scholarship provided by organizer of ISSHID-2019 held on 12th 14th Oct 2019 in Chennai, India.
- DBT-CTEP travel grant awarded to attend a conference on "5th International Viral Hepatitis Elimination Meeting" Amsterdam, Netherlands, 7th 8th December 2018.
- Young investigator IVHEM registration grant: by the Virology Education, organizers of IVHEM-2018 held on December 2018 in Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

Publications:

- Irshad M, <u>Gupta P</u>, Mankotia DS, Ansari MA. Multiplex qPCR for serodetection and serotyping of hepatitis viruses: A brief review. World J Gastroenterol. 2016; 22: 4824-34. PMID: 27239109. DOI: 10.3748/wjg.v22.i20.4824. (IF: 5.742, Citation: 10)
- Irshad M, <u>Gupta P</u>, Irshad K. Molecular basis of hepatocellular carcinoma induced by hepatitis C virus infection. World J Hepatol. 2017; 9: 1305-1314. PMID: 29359013. DOI: 10.4254/wjh.v9.i36.1305. (IF: 0.858, Citation: 43)
- Irshad M, <u>Gupta P</u>, Irshad K. Molecular targeting of antiviral drugs used against hepatitis C virus infection. Hepatoma Res 2018; 4: 23. DOI:10.20517/2394-5079.2018.25 (Citation: 6)
- Irshad M, Mankotia DS, Irshad K, <u>Gupta P</u>. Viral hepatitis in India: Status. Gastroenterol Hepatol Endosc 2018; 3(1): 1-5. DOI: 10.15761/GHE.1000153 (Citation: 1)
- Irshad M, <u>Gupta P</u>, Irshad K. Immunopathogenesis of Liver Injury During Hepatitis C Virus Infection. Viral Immunol. 2019 Feb 28. DOI: 10.1089/vim.2018.0124. PMID: 30817236 (IF: 2.257, Citation: 15)

Conference publication:

- <u>Gupta P</u>, M Irshad, Datta SK. Standardization of TaqMan probe based Hexaplex qPCR Assay for Simultaneous Detection of Hepatitis A-G Viruses. Abstract published in BMC Infect Dis 20, 324 (2020). DOI: 10.1186/s12879-020-05038-y
- Shekhar S, <u>Gupta P</u>, M Irshad. Status of HCV genotypes in patients with different liver diseases using multiplex real time PCR. Abstract published in Ind J Clin Biochem 31, 1–129 (2016). DOI:10.1007/s12291-016-0628-z

<u>Declaration</u>: I hereby declare that all the information provided by me in this application is factual and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.